250 Bryant St. Mountain View, CA 94041 U.S.A.

# ChangSeok Oh

Profile: https://shivamidow.github.io E-mail: changseok@gnome.org Mobile: +1 (404) 740-7896

Open-source hacker and security researcher specializing in web and computer systems. A WebKit, Chromium, and GNOME project contributor. 9 years of industry and 7 years of academic experience. Looking for opportunities in the Web browser, Emerging Web, Browser Security, Web Security & Privacy, and Computer Graphics.

Skills

WebKit, Blink/Chromium, GNOME, Linux, C/C++, Python, HTML/CSS/Javascript, Objective-C, Java, OpenGL/OpenGL ES, Clutter, Computer Graphics, GTK+, eBPF, BCC, Ethereum, Git, OBS, Clang, LLVM, GStreamer, Tizen, Linux Perf, Bluetooth LE, ReactJS, React Native, Embedded system, Puppeteer

#### Education

08/2017 - 12/2022 Ph.D. student (ABD) in Computer Science, Georgia Institute of Technology, U.S.A. 08/2017 - 12/2022 Dual M.S. in Computer Science and Cybersecurity, Georgia Institute of Technology, U.S.A. 03/2000 - 06/2008 Dual B.E. in Digital Media and Computer Engineering, Ajou University, South Korea

### **Professional Experience**

01/2023 - Present	Sr. Software Engineer at ByteDance/TikTok Ltd. in Mountain View, CA
	Working on the Web Platform
	<ul> <li>Web Standardization at the W3C Working Groups: CSS, Performance, WebApp Sec, and Privacy</li> </ul>
06/2019 - 12/2022	Intern at Igalia, S.L. in A Coruña, Spain (cert.)
	Bring ANGLE backend for WebGL to WebKitGTK
	<ul> <li>Zero copy texture sharing between Mesa and ANGLE via Linux DMA buffer</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Research Text-To-Speach technologies to employ for WebKitGTK</li> </ul>
05/2020 - 08/2020	Intern at Samsung Research America in Mountain View, CA
05/2019 - 08/2019	Build a web app for health data analysis with ReactJS (frontend) and Node.js (backend)
	• Built an automated system verifying the UI of a watch app by using the Tizen automation framework
	<ul> <li>Profiled memory usage and revealed possible memory leak of a watch app by using Valgrind</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Implemented file transfer via Bluetooth LE in a React Native watch application</li> </ul>
08/2012 - 03/2016	Software engineer at Collabora Ltd. in Cambridge, UK
	<ul> <li>Developed hardware-based compositing based on Clutter in WebKit</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Resource-efficient web browser based on GNOME Epiphany for Raspberry Pi 2+</li> </ul>
	Customized WebKit features and API set for Smart TV Alliance SDK
07/2008 - 08/2012	Assistant Software engineer at Samsung Electronics in Suwon, South Korea
	• Developed an in-house web layout engine for Smart TVs, Printers in C++
	• Implemented WebGL and Accelerated Compositing in WebKit EFL by using OpenGL ES for Tizen
07/2007 - 06/2008	Intern at Samsung Software Membership in Suwon, South Korea
	<ul> <li>Developed a 3D racing game using DirectX on Windows (video)</li> </ul>

## Academic Experience

	CS 6262: Network Security
05/2021 - 08/2021	· ·
	Research an online ad privacy issue with Prof. Damon McCoy
08/2019 - 05/2021	Teaching Assistant at the School of Computer Science, Georgia Tech
, , , -,	• CS 6262: Network Security, Design, and Implement the XSS task using node is and Chrome Extension
	• CS 6035: Intro to InfoSec
08/2017 - 05/2022	Research Assistant at the School of Computer Science, Georgia Tech
	Study privacy leakage in online ads
	Redesign chromium to block user tracking by web browser fingerprints
	Debloat Chrome browser with feature sunsetting on the fly by binary rewriting
	• Implemented an idle profiler that diagnoses off-CPU time in the multi-threaded programs using HPC
07/2016 - 08/2017	
., ,	• Developed a defense system against micro DDoS by profiling resources with HPC (Intel PCM, MBM)

pen Source Projects		
04/2013 - Present	Committer to WebKit (patches)  • Contribute CSS properties (e.g., font-size-adjust)	
	• Contribute several web features for WebKitGTK (e.g., Form Validation, Gamepad API with libmanette, AVIF support with david, Web Speech Synthesis with Flite and GStreamer, etc.)	
	• Implement OpenGL ES backend for Accelerated Compositing.	
	<ul> <li>Developed memory pressure handler that copes with out-of-memory on top of Linux cgroup.</li> </ul>	
	<ul> <li>Enhance WebGL support and Fix layout and rendering issues</li> </ul>	
	• Fix CVE security bugs in WebKit (CVE-2020-10018, CVE-2020-11793)	
10/2013 - Present	Member of GNOME Foundation (patches)	

• Translate GNOME Web and its Help document in Korean

01/2023 - Present | Instructional Associate at OMSCS, Georgia Tech

01/2015 - Present	Contributor to Chromium/Blink (patches)  • Implemented CSS properties (e.g., font-size-adjust)  • Fix many layout and rendering issues in Blink		
Publications			
ACSAC 2022 ACM CCS 2022 ACM CCS 2020 arXiv:2205.00056	DeView: Confining Progressive Web Applications by Debloating Web APIs (paper) Cart-ology: Intercepting Targeted Advertising via Ad Network Identity Entanglement (paper) Slimium: Debloating the Chromium Browser with Feature Subsetting (paper) Mitigating Low-volume DoS Attacks with Data-driven Resource Accounting (paper)		
Patents			
US9524076B2 US9378300B2 US20110090165A1 US20110289110A1	Web page management method and apparatus and storage medium thereof (alias Tab Group) Interface method and display device (alias Picture-in-Picture Play) Interface method and display device Method of re-searching webpage and apparatus and storage medium therefor		
Talks			
12/09/2022 11/09/2022 12/07/2014 09/29/2014 04/25/2014 10/27/2013	DEVIEW 2014 in Seoul, South Korea (slides, video)		
Services			
04/2023 - Present 10/2021	Representative of ByteDance at W3C Working Groups: CSS, Perf, App Sec, and Privacy Mentoring student participants in the Open-source SW Developer Competition, South Korea (citation)		

Last update: 05/08/2023